Guide to the Sylvère Lotringer Papers and Semiotext(e) Archive, 1960-2004 (Bulk 1973-2000) MSS.221
Fales Library and Special Collections
- OVERSIZE Series II: Semiotext(e) Projects, 189603
  - Subseries A: Issues and Conferences, 208683
    - Anthology "More & Less": Documents, c. 1995; 208742 (Box 93, Folder 9)
    - Conferences "Deleuze (Guattari On the Edge)", 1999; 208743 (Box 93, Folder 10)
    - (unpublished) "Japan Issue": Visual Material, 1990s; 208744 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - (unpublished) "Flesh-Eating Technologies Issue": Visual Material, 2000s; 208745 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Unknown Issue: Layouts, undated; 208746 (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Unknown Issue: Visual Source Material and Layouts, undated; 208747 (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Event "Nova Convention" Poster, 1978; 208895 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    - Special Issue "Loving Boys" layouts, c. 1980; 208898 (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Event "Cemnot3kct" - Poster, c. 1984; 208899 (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - Event "Chance" poster, 1996; 208900 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Foreign, Native and Active Agrents Book Series, 208748
    - Foreign Agents: Unpublished Deleuze Anthology: Texts, 1990s; 208749 (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Native Agents: "William Burroughs Live": Texts, c. 2000; 208750 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Native Agents: "David Wojnarowicz": Press, 2006; 208751 (Box 93, Folder 17)
- OVERSIZE Series III: Manuscripts, 189604
  - Subseries A: Manuscripts, 208795
    - Terence Costello (various mss), 1970s; 208796 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - Unknown author "The Epidog", undated; 208798 (Box 94, Folder 2)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Subject Files, 208799
  - British Rock Lives: Village Voice - March 28, 1977, 208800 (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - I Contact: contact with the lives of Patti Smith, 1977; 208801 (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Punk #17, 1977; 208802 (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Avant-Punk: Village Voice Special Edition, October 24, 1977, 208803 (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Paranoids Anonymous Newsletter #1: Tillman, Lynne, 1976; 208804 (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - La Quinzaine Litteraire: 376 August 1982, 208805 (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Grundberg, Andy (1), Jonathan (2), Laibaros, Joni (1), Mosher, P. (Charlemagne Palestine - 2), various; 208806 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - "Dear Charlotte, 1968 is over..." Kathy Acker poster, 1983; 215626 (Box 94, Folder 9a)
  - "Ashtray" poster, 1991; 215625 (Folder 22)
  - "Antonin Artaud" poster, undated; 215623 (Folder 22)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Sylvere Lotringer Projects, 189605
  - Subseries A: Writing, 208808
    - The New York Times Magazine, July 3, 1977, section 6, "A New Vision of Dreams: Insights from Sleep Research", 208809 (Box 94, Folder 10)
    - Impulse - Death Issue - printed plastic bags (promo), 1985; 208811 (Box 94, Folder 11)
    - Photostats (negatives) of Sylvere's articles in Les Lettres françaises, 215627 (Folder 4 Right)
  - Subseries B: Film, 208897
    - Film "How to Shoot a Crime" poster, undated; 208901 (Box 109)
  - Subseries C: Conferences, Events and Tours, 208810
    - Antonin Artaud Events at the Drawing Centre - poster, 1996; 208812 (Box 94, Folder 12)
    - "The Obesity of Art", undated; 208813 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - "Simone Weil" at Columbia - poster with poster design, undated; 208814 (Box 94, Folder 14)
    - Columbia University Record, November 12, 1999, 208815 (Box 94, Folder 15)
    - "French Theory in America", 1997; 208902 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - "Kafka Colloque", 1989; 208903 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - "The Third Wave: Art and French Theory", undated; 208904 (Box 96, Folder 9)
- OVERSIZE Series VI: Photographic Materials, 189606
  - Subseries A: Professional, 208816
    - Pino Guiseppe (Andy Braxton -2, Unknown Subject -1); Volz, Wolfgang (Christo -1); Watier (2); (S. Lotringer -3); (Deran Ludd - 1); (Unknown Subject -1), 208817 (Box 94, Folder 16)
    - unidentified portraits of a woman, undated; 277181 (Box 95, Folder 11)
- OVERSIZE Series VIII: Clippings and Photocopies, 189607
  - Les Lettres Francaise, various; 208818 (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - "Le Monde", 1974-1975; 208819 (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1968-1979; 208820 (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1980-1989; 208821 (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings, 1996; 208822 (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Paris Lettres & Student (Edinburgh), 1959-1960; 208823 (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Allan, Blaine "Nicholas Ray", undated; 208824 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - clippings: Simone Weil, undated; 208825 (Box 95, Folder 4)
- OVERSIZE Series IX: Copies of Publications, 189608
  - Subseries A: Semiotext(e) Issues, 208826
    - Semiotext(e) Architecture, undated; 208827 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Special Issue: "Loving Boys", 1980; 208828 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Subseries C: Sylvere Lotringer's Publications, 208829
    - Impulse Death Issue, 1985; 208830 (Box 95, Folder 7)
    - Interview with Artaud's Doctor in Impulse, 1988; 208831 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - S.L. Interview in Paper, 1988; 208832 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Interview with Jane Dickson in Bomb, 1997; 208833 (Box 95, Folder 10)
- 2015 Accretion, circa 1980-2004; 276281; Lotringer, Sylvère; 3 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 1 oversized flat box, 1 media box
  Scope and Content
  The accretion is comprised of miscelaneous papers including interviews, syllabi, notes and manuscripts and audio/ visual materials including photographs, casette tapes, VHS tapes, video casette tapes and a film reel covering lectures and media from 1982 through 2003. Topics covered include the creative writing of Walter Abish, versions of the film "How to Shoot a Criminal" and "Second Hand Hitler", recordings of Lotringer speaking on Georges Bataille, and recordings of Paul Virilio.
  Arrangement
  This series has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Donated by Sylvere Lotringer in October 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2015.221
  Abish, Walter
  - Artaud Class at the Art Center, 2003, 276283; 9 audio cassette tapes (Box 108)
  - Dec 2, 04 AA/ Geline, Delive, etc, 2004; 276284; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Bataille, 1992-1998; 276285; 2 audio cassette tapes (Box 108)
  - Creative Write Walter Abish, 276286; 5 Audio Cassette Tapes (Box 108)
  - Consuming Signs Lecture, 2004; 276287; 7 audio cassette tapes (Box 108)
  - Tape of Session with Ranciere, Larmone, Lillo, 276288; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Unidentified Audio Tape 1, 276289; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Trick or Treat Marion Pastor Roces, 1993; 276290; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Celine Feb 12,02, 2002; 276291; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Enclosed in Bubble, 276292; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Extreme art Vienna May 12,01, 2001; 276293; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - For Sylvere From Sam (Graphfeeti Music), 276294; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - Artaud/ Celine Oct 7, 04 Excell, 2004; 276295; Audio Cassette Tape (Box 108)
  - #1 71801 To End (Master Crime), 276296; 1 broadcast videocassette (Box 97)
  - Master Lotringer Krishna, 276297; 1 videocassette (Box 97)
  - Lotringer Film "Second Hand Hitler" Berlin 1982-83 Part II, circa 1982; 276298; VHS (Box 97)
  - Lotringer Film "Second Hand Hitler" Berlin 1982-83 Part I, circa 1982; 276299; VHS (Box 97)
  - How to Shoot a Crime Chris Kraus, 16mm/video, 26:00, 276300; VHS (Box 97)
  - The American Late Show 107, 276310; VHS Tape (Box 97)
  - Heidi IV (221.0037), 276301; VHS (Box 98)
  - Discussion II + Black, telephone sound tests, boys from Brazil, etc, 276302; VHS (Box 98)
  - Hitler Pal I, 276303; VHS (Box 98)
  - Unidentified, 276304; VHS (Box 98)
  - Unidenitifed, 276305; VHS (Box 98)
  - Pal 6, 276306; VHS (Box 98)
  - Reichtag 2 II, 276307; VHS (Box 98)
  - Lotti II 3 Reichtag Cafe Einstein Blue Bumbo Looft I, Hitler in Park PAC, 276308; VHS (Box 98)
  - Virilio 2002, 276282; 5 audio cassette tapes (Box 98)
  - b # 2 Chris Kraus How to Shoot a Crime, 276309; film reel (Box 99)
  - Unprocessed Papers and Photographs, 276311 (Box 100)
- Archived website, November 2017- ongoing; Semiotext(e); 3 websites in 1 collection of archived websites.
  Accruals
  New site crawls are accrued annually.
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code designed to limit crawler activity within a website) was ignored with the permission of the content owner. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.autonomedia.org/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.